A Guide to the Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), General Files, 1962-1976, RG 3 FA094
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), General Files, 1962-1976; 3; 636.07 Cubic Feet 1659 containers - 1591 letter document boxes, 66 legal document boxes, 1 legal tall box, and 1 half-letter box.
  - Rockefeller University, 1962-1976; 30; 13.76 Cubic Feet 35 letter document boxes and 1 legal document box
    - Fairfield Osborn Memorial Lecture in Environmental Science (Box 1576, Folder 4, Box 1577, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center - General, 1966-1976 (Box 1577, Folder 3-4)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center - A-Z (Box 1578, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center - Contributions (Box 1578, Folder 2)
    - Rivers Edge Restaurant (Box 1578, Folder 3)
    - Releases (Box 1578, Folder 4)
    - 75th Anniversary International Conference (Box 1578, Folder 5)
    - Selection Committee (Box 1578, Folder 6)
    - Dr. Frederick Seitz (Box 1579, Folder 1)
    - Student Representative Committee and Student Unrest, 1970 (Box 1579, Folder 2)
    - Sutton House Associates and City Block (Box 1579, Folder 3)
    - Tower Building (Box 1579, Folder 4)
    - Trustees (Box 1579, Folder 5)
    - Works of Art (Box 1580, Folder 1-2)
    - Works of Art - Paintings (Box 1580, Folder 3)
    - Works of Art - David, Jacques-Louis (Box 1580, Folder 4)
  - S, 1962-1976; 31; 3.42 Cubic Feet 9 letter document boxes
    - S - Miscellaneous (Box 1580, Folder 5-6, Box 1581, Folder 1-4, Box 1582, Folder 1)
    - Science - A-Z (Box 1582, Folder 2-3)
    - Science - A-C (Box 1582, Folder 4)
    - Science - D-Z (Box 1583, Folder 1-3)
    - Science - Center for Science in the Public Interest (Box 1584, Folder 1)
    - Science - National Academy of Sciences (Box 1584, Folder 2)
    - Science - New Alchemy Institute (Box 1584, Folder 3)
    - Science - New York Academy of Sciences (Box 1584, Folder 4)
    - Sealantic Fund (Box 1584, Folder 5, Box 1585, Folder 1)
    - Seal Harbor Organizations (Box 1585, Folder 3-4)
    - Sealantic Fund - By-Laws (Box 1585, Folder 2)
    - Seal Harbor Organizations - North East Harbor Fleet (Box 1585, Folder 5)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations (Box 1589, Folder 2-3)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - A-Z (Box 1589, Folder 4)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - Board of Trustees (Box 1590, Folder 1)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - Board of Trustees - Mrs. Nelson A. Rockefeller, Happy (Box 1590, Folder 2)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - Boyer, A. (Box 1590, Folder 3)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - Boyer, A. - New York Office (Box 1590, Folder 4)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - Five Year Plan - Cater, 1955 (Box 1590, Folder 5)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - Clippings (Box 1590, Folder 6)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - Printed Material (Box 1586, Folder 1-2)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - History (Box 1586, Folder 3)
  - T-W, 1962-1976; 32; 3.13 Cubic Feet 7 letter document boxes and 1 legal box
    - T - Miscellaneous (Box 1586, Folder 4, Box 1587, Folder 1)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - Richford - John D. Rockefeller Birthplace - Correspondence, 1968-1980 (Box 1588, Folder 1)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - Richford - John D. Rockefeller Birthplace - Correspondence - Ray Rockefeller, 1969-1976 (Box 1588, Folder 2)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - Richford - John D. Rockefeller Birthplace - Correspondence and Memos - Dana Creel, 1967-1977 (Box 1588, Folder 3)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - Richford - John D. Rockefeller Birthplace - Memos and Reports, 1967-1975 (Box 1588, Folder 4)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - Richford - John D. Rockefeller Birthplace - Newspaper Clippings, 1877-1980 (Box 1588, Folder 5)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - Richford - John D. Rockefeller Birthplace - Newspaper Clippings - Ray Rockefeller Column, 1960, 1967-1976 (Box 1588, Folder 6)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - Richford - John D. Rockefeller Birthplace - Research Notes, Maps, Plans (Box 1588, Folder 7)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - William Avery Rockefeller - William Levingston - Report - Joseph W. Ernst (Box 1588, Folder 8)
    - Tioga - Rockefeller Family & Associates - Archives - William Avery Rockefeller - William Levingston - Research Notes - Joseph W. Ernst (Box 1588, Folder 9)
    - U - Miscellaneous (Box 1587, Folder 2-3)
    - V - Miscellaneous (Box 1587, Folder 4-5)
    - W - Miscellaneous (Box 1587, Folder 6, Box 1589, Folder 1)
    - Westchester Organizations (Box 1619, Folder 4, Box 1620, Folder 1)
    - Westchester Organizations - Westchester County Department of Planning (Box 1620, Folder 2-5, Box 1621, Folder 1-4)
    - Westchester Organizations - Westchester County Department of Planning - Printed Material (Box 1622, Folder 1-3)
  - Welfare, 1962-1976; 33; 11.01 Cubic Feet 29 letter document boxes
    - Welfare - A-G (Box 1591, Folder 1-3)
    - Welfare - A-M (Box 1592, Folder 1-5)
    - Welfare - N-P (Box 1593, Folder 1-4)
    - Welfare - O-T (Box 1594, Folder 1-4)
    - Welfare - T-Z (Box 1595, Folder 1-4)
    - American Red Cross (Box 1596, Folder 1-2)
    - American Red Cross - Contributions (Box 1596, Folder 3-4)
    - Arkansas Institute for Social Justice, Inc. (Box 1596, Folder 5, Box 1597, Folder 1)
    - Association for International Child Welfare (Box 1597, Folder 2)
    - Child Study Association of America (Box 1597, Folder 3)
    - Community Service Society (NY) (Box 1597, Folder 4)
    - Cut Cane Associates (Box 1597, Folder 5)
    - Delta Foundation (Box 1597, Folder 6)
    - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York (Box 1597, Folder 7)
    - Goodwill Industries of Greater New York (Box 1598, Folder 1)
    - Homeworkers Organized for More Employment (H.O.M.E) (Box 1598, Folder 2)
    - NY Times Neediest Cases (Box 1598, Folder 3)
    - Opportunities Industrialization Centers of Greater Boston (Box 1598, Folder 4)
    - Visiting Nurse Service of New York (Box 1598, Folder 5)
    - Animals (Box 1598, Folder 6)
    - Animals - A-Z (Box 1599, Folder 1-4)
    - Animals - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (Box 1600, Folder 1)
    - Animals - Animal Welfare Institute (Box 1600, Folder 2)
    - Blind - A-B (Box 1600, Folder 3-4)
    - Blind - A-Z (Box 1601, Folder 1-3)
    - Blind - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness (Box 1602, Folder 1-2)
    - Blind - New York Association of the Blind (Box 1602, Folder 3)
    - Blind - Recording for the Blind (Box 1602, Folder 4)
    - Community Centers - A-E (Box 1602, Folder 5-6)
    - Community Centers - F-M (Box 1603, Folder 1-3)
    - Community Centers - L-Z (Box 1604, Folder 1-2)
    - Community Centers - Community Opportunity Center of the Tarrytowns (Box 1604, Folder 3)
    - Community Centers - Goddard - Riverside Community Center (Box 1604, Folder 4)
    - Community Centers - Henry Street Settlement (Box 1604, Folder 5)
    - Community Centers - Lenox Hill Neighborhood Association (Box 1605, Folder 1)
    - Community Centers - Lenox Hill Neighborhood Association - Mrs. LSR Contributions for ADS in Benefit Program, 1957-1968 (Box 1605, Folder 2)
    - Community Centers - Lincoln Square Neighborhood Center (Box 1605, Folder 3)
    - Community Centers - Union Settlement Association (Box 1605, Folder 4)
    - Community Centers - United Neighborhood Houses of New York, Inc. (Box 1606, Folder 1)
    - Community Centers - Alfred T. While Community Center (Box 1606, Folder 2)
      Formerly Brooklyn Community Center
    - Community Chests (Box 1606, Folder 3)
    - Crime Prevention - A-M (Box 1606, Folder 4-5)
    - Crime Prevention - M-Z (Box 1607, Folder 1-2)
    - Crime Prevention - National Council on Crime Delinquency (Box 1607, Folder 3)
    - Crime Prevention - Osborne Association (Box 1607, Folder 4)
    - Crime Prevention - Westchester Citizens Committee of the NCCD (Box 1607, Folder 5)
    - Day Nurseries (Box 1608, Folder 1-2)
    - Family Counseling (Box 1608, Folder 3)
    - Handicapped - A-H (Box 1608, Folder 4-5)
    - Handicapped - I-Z (Box 1609, Folder 1-4)
    - Handicapped - A-Z (Box 1610, Folder 1-3)
    - Handicapped - Association for the help of Retarded Children (Box 1611, Folder 1)
    - Handicapped - Institute for the Crippled and Disabled (Box 1611, Folder 2)
    - Handicapped - Speech rehabilitation Institute (Box 1611, Folder 3)
    - Homes (Box 1611, Folder 4)
    - Homes - A-O (Box 1611, Folder 5-6)
    - Homes - P-Z (Box 1612, Folder 1)
    - Homes - Pilgrim Place (Box 1612, Folder 2)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - A-L (Box 1612, Folder 3)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - A-Z (Box 1613, Folder 1-4, Box 1614, Folder 1)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - Coalition of Eastern Native Americans (Box 1614, Folder 2)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - DNA - People's Legal Service Inc. (Box 1614, Folder 3)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - Institute for the Development of Indian Law (Box 1614, Folder 4)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - The Youth Project (Committee to Save Black Mesa) (Box 1615, Folder 1)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - The Youth Project - Printed material (Box 1615, Folder 2)
    - Legal (Box 1615, Folder 3)
    - Legal - Legal Aid Society (Box 1615, Folder 4)
    - Legal - A-Z (Box 1616, Folder 1-2)
    - Legal - Action for Legal Rights (Box 1616, Folder 3)
    - Legal - Action for Legal Rights - Contributions (Box 1616, Folder 4)
    - Legal - Southern Coalition on Jail and Prisons (Box 1617, Folder 1)
    - Musicians Aid Society (Box 1617, Folder 2)
    - Musicians Emergency Fund/Hospitalized Veterans Service (Box 1617, Folder 3)
    - Orphans (Box 1617, Folder 4-5)
    - Orphans - Spence Chaplin Adoption Service (Box 1617, Folder 6)
    - United Funds (Box 1618, Folder 1-2)
    - United Fund of Greater New York 1969 Campaign Fund (Box 1618, Folder 3)
    - United Service Organizations (USO) (Box 1619, Folder 1-2)
    - United Service Organizations (USO) - Greater New York (Box 1619, Folder 3)
  - Women (Role of), 1962-1976; 34; 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
    - Women (Role of) (Box 1622, Folder 4, Box 1623, Folder 1)
    - National Council of Women of the U.S. (Box 1623, Folder 2)
    - United Nations - International Women's Year World Plan of Action Digest: Weal, 1975 June (Box 1623, Folder 3)
    - United Nations - International Women's Year and Conference, 1975 June (Box 1623, Folder 4)
    - United Nations - International Women's Year and Conference - Tribune, 1975 June (Box 1623, Folder 5)
    - United Nations - International Women's Year and Conference - UN Conference, 1975 June (Box 1624, Folder 1)
    - United Nations - International Women's Year and Conference - Proposals, 1975 June (Box 1624, Folder 2)
    - United Nations - International Women's Year and Conference - Documents, 1975 June (Box 1624, Folder 3-4)
    - United Nations - International Women's Year and Conference - Clippings, 1975 June (Box 1625, Folder 1)
  - Youth, 1962-1976; 35; 10.63 Cubic Feet 28 letter document boxes
    - Youth - A-Z, 1
      - Youth - A-C (Box 1625, Folder 4, Box 1626, Folder 1-3)
      - Youth - C-H (Box 1627, Folder 1-5)
      - Youth - G-O (Box 1628, Folder 1-4)
      - Youth - N-V (Box 1629, Folder 1-3)
      - Youth - S-Z (Box 1630, Folder 1-3, Box 1631, Folder 1)
      - American Youth hostels (Box 1631, Folder 2)
      - Big Brothers and Big Sisters (Box 1631, Folder 3-4)
      - Boy Scouts of America - A-K (Box 1631, Folder 5-6)
      - Boy Scouts of America - L-Z (Box 1632, Folder 1-2)
      - Boys Scouts of America - Greater New York Council (Box 1632, Folder 3-4)
      - Boys Scouts of America - Virgin Islands District Committee (Box 1633, Folder 1-2)
      - Boys Club of America (Box 1633, Folder 3)
      - Boys Club of New York (Box 1633, Folder 4)
      - Child Welfare League of America (Box 1633, Folder 5)
      - Children's Aid Society (Box 1633, Folder 6, Box 1634, Folder 1)
      - Day Care and Child Development Council of America (Box 1633, Folder 7, Box 1634, Folder 2)
      - Duke Edinburgh Award Scheme (Box 1634, Folder 3)
      - European Working Group (Box 1634, Folder 4)
      - Girls Scouts of America - Girls Scout Council of Greater NY (Camp High Rock) (Box 1635, Folder 1)
      - Girls Scout of America (Box 1634, Folder 5-6)
      - Junior Achievement of NY, Inc (Box 1635, Folder 2)
      - New York City - Mayor's Summer Task Force (Box 1635, Folder 3)
      - Police Athletic League (Box 1635, Folder 4)
      - President's Council on Youth Opportunity (Box 1635, Folder 5)
      - Putnam Children's Center (James Jackson Putnam Children's Center) (Box 1635, Folder 6, Box 1636, Folder 1)
      - JDR 3rd - A-Z (Box 1636, Folder 2-3)
      - JDR 3rd - Memos/Meetings, 1969 (Box 1636, Folder 4)
      - JDR 3rd - Project 3, 1973 August 30 (Box 1636, Folder 5, Box 1637, Folder 1)
      - JDR 3rd - Printed material (Box 1637, Folder 2)
      - JDR 3rd - Yankelovich Report (Box 1637, Folder 3-4)
      - JDR 3rd - Yankelovich Report - Public Affairs (Box 1637, Folder 5)
      - JDR 3rd - D.C, Smith - Five Colleges Inc. (Box 1638, Folder 1-2)
      - Save the Children Federation (Box 1638, Folder 3-4)
      - Vocational Advisory Service (Box 1638, Folder 5)
      - Vocational Foundation, Inc. (Box 1638, Folder 6)
      - West Virginia Service Corps (Box 1639, Folder 1)
      - Williamsburg Area Recreational Association (Box 1639, Folder 2)
      - Young Men Christian Association (YMCA) (Box 1639, Folder 3-4)
      - Young Men Christian Association (YMCA) - YMCA/YWCA merger (Box 1640, Folder 1-2)
      - Young Men Christian Association (YMCA) - Puerto Rico (Box 1640, Folder 3-4)
      - Young Men Christian Association (YMCA) - Greater NY (Box 1640, Folder 5)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) (Box 1641, Folder 1-2)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - Contributions (Box 1641, Folder 3-4)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - Hawaii - Donation of Hapuna Beach Building (Box 1641, Folder 5)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - New York City (Box 1642, Folder 1-2)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - New York City - Contributions (Box 1642, Folder 3)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - New York City - Over All Anniversary Committee (Box 1642, Folder 4-5)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Property - Possible Sale (Box 1642, Folder 6)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - Printed material (Box 1643, Folder 1-2)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - White Plains and Central Westchester (Box 1643, Folder 3)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board (Box 1643, Folder 4-5)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - A-Z (Box 1644, Folder 1)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Board of Trustees (Box 1644, Folder 2-3)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Conference at Jackson Hole, 1964 July (Box 1644, Folder 4)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Contributions (Box 1644, Folder 5-6)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Finances (Box 1645, Folder 1-2)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Fund raising (Box 1645, Folder 3)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - International Division (Box 1645, Folder 4)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - International Division - Contributions (Box 1645, Folder 5)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - International Division - International Building Fund Brochure (Box 1646, Folder 1)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Printed Material (Box 1646, Folder 2)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Marion O. Robinson Book (Box 1646, Folder 3)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Marion O. Robinson Book - Printer's manuscript (Box 1647, Folder 1-2)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Mr. and Mrs. LSR Trip, 1963 (Box 1647, Folder 3)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Mr. and Mrs. LSR Trip - Mary French Rockefeller Article (Box 1647, Folder 4)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - National Board - Mr. and Mrs. LSR Trip - Mary French Rockefeller Article - Acknowledgements (Box 1648, Folder 1-2)
      - Young Women Christian Association (YWCA) - YWCA World Mutual Service - A Common Quest (Box 1648, Folder 3)
      - Youth Development, Inc. (Box 1648, Folder 4)
      - Youth Organizations United (Box 1648, Folder 5, Box 1649, Folder 1)
    - Camps, 2
      - Camps (Box 1649, Folder 2-3, Box 1650, Folder 1)
      - Encampment for Citizenship Inc. (Box 1650, Folder 2)
      - Fresh Air Fund (Box 1650, Folder 3-4)
      - Fresh Air Fund - Printed Material (Box 1650, Folder 5)
      - Fresh Air Fund - Contributions (Box 1651, Folder 1)
      - Fresh Air Association of St. John (Box 1651, Folder 2)
    - Homes, 3
      - Homes - A-H (Box 1651, Folder 3-5)
      - Homes - I-Z (Box 1652, Folder 1-2)
      - Children's Village (Box 1652, Folder 3)
      - Our Little Brothers and Sisters (Box 1652, Folder 4)
        Formerly Father Wassous Boys Home
      - Saint Mary's in the Field (Box 1652, Folder 5)
  - X-Y-Z, 1962-1976; 36; 0.85 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box and 1 legal document box
    - X and Y - Miscellaneous (Box 1625, Folder 2)
    - Young, Kenneth T., Jr. (Box 1625, Folder 3)
    - Z - Miscellaneous (Box 1653, Folder 1)
  - Audiovisual Materials, 1966-1976; 37; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
    Sound recordings
    - David Rockefeller-William Wing Project, 1975-1976
      - Julian Levi, 1976 July 14; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15608A)
        Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
      - William Moody, 1976 August 26; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15608B)
      - David Rockefeller, 1976? July 22; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15609A)
      - David Rockefeller-Warren Lindquist-William Wing-Rick Salomon-Joe Ernst, 1976? July 22; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15609B)
      - Warren T. Lindquist, 1976 January 13; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15610)
      - David Rockefeller - Warren Lindquist - William Wing - Joe Ernst, 1975 July 10; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15611)
      - David Rockefeller Conversations, 1975 July 22; 1/4 audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15607)
    - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Radio and Television - "Beautify America" - Cuts 1-12, 1966 June; 1/4 audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15605)
      Access copy currently unavailable. See a RAC archivist for further instruction.
      Produced with the cooperation of the White House by the radio stations of the Storer Broadcasting Company. Introductions by Jim Ameche.
    - Rockefeller Family & Associates/Rockefeller Family Office - Public Affairs - Ira Liebowitz Interview, Air dates: 1974 December 2 and 8; 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15606)
      General
      Contained a types letter to Nelson Rockefeller from Denise Krumm, Program Cccordinator/ Ultravision Broadcasting Company, Inc., dated November 22,
      "Dear Sir, Enclosed is an audio tape recording of a public service program which was recorded today for our playback on December 2nd and December 8th, 1974
      The guest on the show, Ira Liebowitz, made strong accusations about you and we felt that you would want to listen to this tape.
      If you wish to respond we will make our station available to you at your convenience."
      (Handwritten on top: "No reply")
  - Archives, Tioga Photographs, 1037; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
    Photographs
    - Richford - JDR Birthplace (Box 14, Folder 180)
      Scope and Contents note
      Richford, JDR, houses, landscape
    - William Avery Rockefeller -William Levingston Report - Joseph W. Ernst (Box 14, Folder 181)
      Levingston home, Cemeteries, Graves, Ranches, Illinois, North Dakota